<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Aerlytix News</title>
	<subtitle>A feed of the latest news about what we are doing.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www.aerlytix.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.aerlytix.com/"/>
	<updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.aerlytix.com</id>
	<author>
    <name>Aerlytix</name>
    <email>info@aerlytix.com</email>
	</author>
	
    
    <entry>
      <title>Aerlytix Welcomes Industry Veteran Thought-Leader Nils Hallerstrom as Advisor</title>
      <link href="https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/aerlytix-welcomes-industry-veteran-thought-leader-nils-hallerstrom-as-advisor/"/>
      <updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/aerlytix-welcomes-industry-veteran-thought-leader-nils-hallerstrom-as-advisor/</id>
      <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>We are thrilled to announce that Nils Hallerstrom is joining Aerlytix as an advisor. Nils [linkedin tag]  has a remarkable track record of advancing aviation risk management whilst delivering pioneering financial solutions. This brings a wealth of expertise to Aerlytix that is perfectly aligned with our drive to deliver industry-leading technology to our clients.</p>
<p>As Aerlytix continues to innovate and expand our stochastic modelling and credit risk product range, Nils' deep industry knowledge will be invaluable.
Combined with our cutting-edge technology stack, his expertise will enhance our ability to provide our clients with groundbreaking tools to manage aviation financial risk more effectively.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more updates as we go from strength to strength over the coming months.
<br/>
<br /></p>

      ]]></content>
    </entry>
	
    
    <entry>
      <title>5 Ways Our Customers Leverage the Aerlytix Excel Add-in</title>
      <link href="https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/5-ways-our-customers-leverage-the-aerlytix-excel-add-in/"/>
      <updated>2024-03-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/5-ways-our-customers-leverage-the-aerlytix-excel-add-in/</id>
      <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>With 750 million users worldwide, Excel is the go-to for any financial analysis. The aviation finance industry is no exception in relying on the spreadsheet software for investment analysis.</p>
<p>However, as customer fleets grow, reliance on Excel alone for asset management leads to inefficient processes and any envisaged economies of scale are lost.
<br/>
<br /></p>
<h3>Drawbacks of Excel for aviation asset management</h3>
<br />
<p><strong>Change Management / Version Control</strong> – once a spreadsheet is shared, tracking changes across an organization is unworkable, especially as users grow. Identification of the “latest or correct” version causes delay in time-to-market.</p>
<p><strong>Key-person risk</strong> – for good reasons, asset forecasting and valuation models undergo many version updates as requirements evolve – each iteration making the Excel model more esoteric. Consequently, there is one or at best a handful of personnel depended upon to competently run/validate the Excel model.  Over time, this situation culminates in legacy, handover and model IP issues as individuals inevitably move on. there is often one person responsible for running legacy pricing spreadsheet models: “the model guy”. But when that person is away or leaves the company, getting the next person up to speed can bring workflows to a screeching halt.</p>
<p><strong>Security</strong> – while cloud environments are generally secure, it is all too easy to download a spreadsheet file locally, leaving an organization exposed to data and intellectual property loss. Limited data security exists within spreadsheets to protect against the loss of intellectual property (IP).</p>
<p><strong>Absence of Integration and Automation</strong> – perhaps its greatest drawback, Excel’s lack of automation and database connectivity leads to onerous periodic processes for portfolio and fleet managers in maintaining technical and lease statuses for forecasting. Such manual processes are prone to greater operational risk from human errors, e.g. copy-paste. Beyond the risk of human error, duplicative data entry for mundane monthly reporting leads to unnecessary headcount growth.</p>
<p><strong>Large Data Limitations</strong> – Excel suffers performance issues when dealing with large datasets stored within sheets. Externally linked datasets only increase the potential for data corruption; and therefore, wasted effort. Every analyst has faced the daunting task of opening a 20+ MB file.
<br />
<br /></p>
<h3>How Aerlytix overcomes these challenges?</h3>
<br />
<p>At Aerlytix, we recognize the ubiquity of Excel and how it is embedded as a primary 'front-end' for diverse functions across a business.</p>
<p>The Aerlytix Excel Add-in gives direct in-cell query access to all current and forecasted outputs from the Analytics Suite. Querying is performed within a spreadsheet cell via the Aerlytix (“.AX”) custom function library – containing 500+ custom query functions.</p>
<script src="https://fast.wistia.com/embed/medias/th5qea4wat.jsonp" async></script><script src="https://fast.wistia.com/assets/external/E-v1.js" async></script><div class="wistia_responsive_padding" style="padding:56.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;"><div class="wistia_responsive_wrapper" style="height:100%;left:0;position:absolute;top:0;width:100%;"><div class="wistia_embed wistia_async_th5qea4wat seo=true videoFoam=true" style="height:100%;position:relative;width:100%">&nbsp;</div></div></div><br/>
<caption>You can read more on our [maintenance module page](/products/maintenance-forecasting/)</caption>
<p><strong>Pricing Model Integration</strong> – Aerlytix customers continue to use their Excel-based pricing spreadsheets, with all core maintenance and lease cashflows originating from the Analytics Suite. Previously heavy spreadsheets become just another “light front-end view” to the Aerlytix application. Users confidently price individual aircraft and portfolios, maintaining a consistent assumption basis while ensuring auditability.</p>
<p><strong>Automated Maintenance Cashflows</strong> – Aerlytix integrates with both industry leading appraisers, and the major asset management systems relied upon by the aviation industry. Previously stagnant contracts management data and utilization reports are available at the fingertips of portfolio managers to extract on-the-fly cashflows via Excel Add-in custom functions. Execute strategy with the most up-to-date data available.</p>
<p><strong>“Go-to” Approval Papers</strong>– the Aerlytix product suite enables users to work with unparalleled efficiency, however management still want approval papers and reporting in the ‘normal template’. The Excel Add-in allows users to quickly update standard budget templates, investment memos, actual investment performance, and FP&amp;A reports in seconds.</p>
<p><strong>Bespoke Technical Analysis</strong> – the Analytics Suite enables users to make sophisticated maintenance forecast decisions with intuitive graphs, visualization, and hundreds of scenario parameters. Technical teams can then extract the lowest level of LLP detail directly into bespoke part-out models with the Excel Add-in.</p>
<p><strong>Sophisticated Debt Structuring</strong> – Aerlytix has a proven ability to scale to fleets exceeding +600 aircraft. Customers keep complex debt structures such as ABS waterfalls and warehouse facilities up-to-date with the ability to refresh portfolio cashflows and stress-test DSCRs with “what-if” analysis in seconds.</p>
<p>The Aerlytix Excel Add-in gives every user the capability to connect any spreadsheet to the Aerlytix Analytics Suite, ensuring maximum output flexibility - all wrapped within the permissions, controls and security of the Analytics Suite. All at no additional cost.</p>
<p>Sitting within every Aerlytix customers’ excel ribbon is the Aerlytix Excel Add-in application.</p>
<p>For more details <a href="/company/contact-us/">contact us</a> or <a href="/request-demo">request a demo</a>.</p>

      ]]></content>
    </entry>
	
    
    <entry>
      <title>Aerlytix partners with Stratos to Transform Aircraft ABS Reporting</title>
      <link href="https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/aerlytix-partners-with-stratos-to-transform-aircraft-abs-reporting/"/>
      <updated>2023-11-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/aerlytix-partners-with-stratos-to-transform-aircraft-abs-reporting/</id>
      <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <blockquote class="callout callout__info" style="margin-bottom:28px">
<p> <svg width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" style="margin-top:-3px">
<path d="M12 22C17.5228 22 22 17.5228 22 12C22 6.47715 17.5228 2 12 2C6.47715 2 2 6.47715 2 12C2 17.5228 6.47715 22 12 22Z" stroke="black" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"/>
<path d="M12 16V12" stroke="black" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"/>
<path d="M12 8H12.01" stroke="black" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"/>
</svg> <strong>NOTE:</strong> Article originally published in AirFinance Journal: <a href="https://www.airfinancejournal.com/articles/3592323/exclusive-stratos-launches-abs-portal">Exclusive: Stratos Launches ABS Portal</a></p>
<svg class="airfinance-logo" viewBox="0 0 769 259">
<style type="text/css">
	.st0{fill:#26282A;}
	.st1{fill:#0076A9;}
	.st2{fill:#0698D6;}
</style>
<g>
	<g>
		<g>
			<path class="st0" d="M303.76,118.55L298,104.22h-30.85l-5.77,14.33h-5.77l23.86-58.29h6.2l23.86,58.29H303.76z M282.53,65.59
				l-13.72,34.08h27.53L282.53,65.59z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M318.1,118.55V60.26h4.98v58.29H318.1z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M371.76,118.55l-16.34-24.12h-12.85v24.12h-4.98V60.26h21.76c10.05,0,17.74,6.38,17.74,17.04
				c0,10.57-7.52,16.43-16.17,16.78l16.87,24.47H371.76z M371.85,77.3c0-7.34-5.24-12.5-12.93-12.5h-16.34v25.08h16.34
				C366.6,89.89,371.85,84.65,371.85,77.3z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M389.51,118.55V60.26h36.97v4.54h-31.99v21.59h31.38v4.54h-31.38v27.61H389.51z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M436.87,118.55V60.26h4.98v58.29H436.87z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M498.05,118.55l-36.7-50.08v50.08h-4.98V60.26h5.07l36.53,49.38V60.26h4.98v58.29H498.05z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M559.66,118.55l-5.77-14.33h-30.85l-5.77,14.33h-5.77l23.86-58.29h6.2l23.86,58.29H559.66z M538.43,65.59
				l-13.72,34.08h27.53L538.43,65.59z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M615.69,118.55l-36.7-50.08v50.08H574V60.26h5.07l36.53,49.38V60.26h4.98v58.29H615.69z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M632.91,89.45c0-17.92,13.02-30.15,29.54-30.15c9.26,0,16.26,4.11,21.24,10.31l-4.19,2.71
				c-3.67-5.07-10.05-8.48-17.04-8.48c-13.72,0-24.29,10.4-24.29,25.61c0,15.03,10.58,25.61,24.29,25.61
				c6.99,0,13.37-3.41,17.04-8.48l4.19,2.62c-5.16,6.38-11.97,10.4-21.24,10.4C645.93,119.6,632.91,107.37,632.91,89.45z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M693.82,118.55V60.26h36.97v4.54H698.8v21.59h31.38v4.54H698.8v23.07h31.99v4.54H693.82z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M255.7,191.67l2.36-2.1c2.71,3.84,6.47,7.08,12.41,7.08c8.65,0,13.98-6.03,13.98-14.59v-42.12h2.8v42.12
				c0,11.62-7.78,17.21-16.78,17.21C264.09,199.27,259.46,196.91,255.7,191.67z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M300.62,169.12c0-16.87,10.75-30.15,27.7-30.15c16.87,0,27.7,13.28,27.7,30.15
				c0,16.87-10.84,30.15-27.7,30.15C311.37,199.27,300.62,185.99,300.62,169.12z M352.97,169.12c0-15.99-9.7-27.53-24.64-27.53
				c-15.12,0-24.64,11.53-24.64,27.53c0,15.82,9.52,27.53,24.64,27.53C343.27,196.65,352.97,184.94,352.97,169.12z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M369.4,176.11v-36.18h2.8v36.18c0,12.93,6.64,20.54,18.88,20.54s18.88-7.6,18.88-20.54v-36.18h2.8v36.18
				c0,14.42-7.52,23.16-21.67,23.16C376.92,199.27,369.4,190.44,369.4,176.11z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M462.66,198.22l-17.74-25.17h-13.98v25.17h-2.8v-58.29h20.1c9.44,0,17.22,5.86,17.22,16.52
				c0,10.66-7.78,16.6-17.22,16.6l18,25.17H462.66z M462.39,156.45c0-8.04-5.59-13.9-14.16-13.9h-17.31v27.88h17.31
				C456.8,170.43,462.39,164.49,462.39,156.45z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M520.86,198.22l-39.33-53.75v53.75h-2.8v-58.29h2.8l39.33,53.22v-53.22h2.8v58.29H520.86z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M581.86,198.22l-6.46-15.64h-32.51l-6.47,15.64h-3.23l24.29-58.29h3.32l24.29,58.29H581.86z M559.14,143.16
				l-15.21,36.79h30.41L559.14,143.16z"></path>
			<path class="st0" d="M594.63,198.22v-58.29h2.8v55.67h29.28v2.62H594.63z"></path>
		</g>
		<g>
			<polygon class="st1" points="16.44,240.09 70.78,205.71 121.56,97.95 121.56,18.48 			"></polygon>
			<polygon class="st2" points="226.67,240.09 172.33,205.71 121.56,97.95 121.56,18.48 			"></polygon>
		</g>
	</g>
</g>
</svg>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Dublin, Ireland – November 27, 2023:</strong> Asset manager and servicer Stratos has launched an innovative reporting system for its asset-backed securitization (ABS) Jol-Air 2019.</p>
<p>The enhanced reporting portal features information per aircraft MSN on lease rate ranges, maintenance status, forward maintenance projections, and estimated end-of-lease compensation payments for investors.</p>
<p>In an interview with Airfinance Journal, Chief Executive Officer Gary Fitzgerald says the product was launched on 14 November with technology solutions company Aerlytix.</p>
<p>Aerlytix CEO Alan Doyle expresses his satisfaction with the collaboration with Stratos in developing an ABS investor portal for the JOL Air-2019 ABS.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;We are delighted to partner with Stratos to enhance the analysis available for ABS investors. This product, designed to extend across all ABSs, will drive transparency and productivity in the industry. Overall, it enhances our expanding suite of offerings to lessors, banks, and investors.&quot;</p>
<p><cite>Alan Doyle - Aerlytix CEO</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fitzgerald says the reporting system was prompted by investor inquiries trying to understand value in the ABS market over recent years.
&quot;Before Covid, details in an ABS monthly noteholder report were not too much of an issue for noteholders or even for secondary trading,&quot; he comments.</p>
<p>&quot;But after some heavy lease restructurings related to Covid, investors have struggled to value ABS holdings and have recently inquired about breakdowns per aircraft, jurisdictions, maintenance status, etc. Having conversations with them, we realized that they have been missing crucial information on all aircraft ABS transactions.&quot;</p>
<p>He says that in ABS deals noteholders receive monthly reports which are without much substance.</p>
<p>&quot;For instance, noteholders get the full total amount of income but no breakdown per aircraft, no accurate maintenance status, and no end-of-lease details.</p>
<p>He adds: &quot;Limited reporting is a legacy issue from the early 1990s when securitization transactions in the aircraft finance market started. This became the template for aircraft ABS issuances and as a result, they have become the most opaque structured asset instruments – unlike car loans, containers, rail car industries where information on individual loans is available for most transactions.&quot;</p>
<p>He believes that this reporting system should become normal reporting for ABS structures.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had hugely positive feedback from the biggest noteholders in our securitizations. Investors can access the platform at any time rather than waiting for a monthly noteholder report; they can finally establish a valuation from the bottom up.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have turned ourselves into a digital servicer by allowing our clients to access their aircraft and see the details of their investments.&quot;</p>
<p>Fitzgerald says Stratos is differentiating itself from other platforms, especially the large asset managers and lessors, which may have hundreds of aircraft in their portfolios and ABS structures.</p>
<p>&quot;For us, using the system is about opening access to our investors. Some lessors use the system for their own pricing models, but if you are a large lessor with a portion of ABS exposure, you may not want to share information to this level for just a small portion of your overall portfolio.&quot;</p>
<p>Fitzgerald says the ABS sector has to become more transparent. &quot;In the capital markets, the primary issuances are bought by say 20-30 institutions that may invest $5 million up to $100 million worth of notes. But the secondary trading is very small and relatively inactive.&quot;</p>
<p>He adds that occasionally some opportunistic buyers may jump into the market and have access to some heavily discounted notes, but they are trading on bond economics and not kept up to date on exactly how each portfolio has developed.</p>
<p>&quot;This product helps every institution to better understand the value of its underlying asset investment.&quot;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;This product helps every institution to better understand the value of its underlying asset investment.&quot;</p>
<p><cite>Gary Fitzgerald - Stratos CEO</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fitzgerald believes that the wider use among the asset managers should ‘massively’ increase liquidity in secondary ABS market trading.</p>
<p>&quot;Removing opacity in this segment can only improve attractiveness for bonds,&quot; he adds.</p>
<p>For him, banks have been slowly pulling away from the aircraft finance sector because of the cost of capital allocation and increasingly punitive regulation affecting the banking sector.</p>
<p>&quot;The only segment large enough to replace such a huge volume of bank lending capacity over time is the capital markets where you have properly rated, properly reported securitized structures which are re-traded in a liquid secondary market so they can be underwritten by pension funds and insurers. Up to now, there has been relatively little trading in the secondary market, and we need to change this momentum.&quot;</p>

      ]]></content>
    </entry>
	
    
    <entry>
      <title>The Aerlytix team moves into new headquarters in the centre of Dublin</title>
      <link href="https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/the-aerlytix-team-moves-into-new-headquarters-in-the-centre-of-dublin/"/>
      <updated>2023-10-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/the-aerlytix-team-moves-into-new-headquarters-in-the-centre-of-dublin/</id>
      <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Dublin, Ireland – October 2023:</strong> Aerlytix, the aviation industry technology solutions company, has opened its new office at 1862 Barrow, 1A Barrow Street, Dublin, D04 E9R0, Ireland.</p>
<p>As one of the fastest growing aviation technology companies in Ireland, Aerlytix now has room to continue its rapid growth trajectory. After a long time working from home, the Aerlytix team are delighted to be working under the same roof as the company continues to expand.</p>
<p>Aerlytix is retaining its hybrid office-remote working policy but delighted to have a central location to meet with colleagues, clients and industry executives in the busy months ahead.</p>
<p>Located at 1862 Barrow, 1A Barrow Street, Dublin, D04 E9R0, Ireland, the Aerlytix team are in the centre of the aviation finance and leasing community in the city and are looking forward to continuing to reconnect with the industry, at short notice, from a more central base.</p>
<p>“Although we remain fans of the hybrid remote working model, it is very exciting to have the team all under one roof,” says Alan Doyle, Chief Executive Officer, Aerlytix. “With a busy year ahead, with more announcements planned this year, it is a great time to work at Aerlytix.”</p>

      ]]></content>
    </entry>
	
    
    <entry>
      <title>Aerlytix wins Technology Innovation of the Year Award 2022</title>
      <link href="https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/aerlytix-wins-technology-innovation-of-the-year-award-2022/"/>
      <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/aerlytix-wins-technology-innovation-of-the-year-award-2022/</id>
      <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Dublin, Ireland – May 3, 2022:</strong> Aerlytix has been awarded the Airline Economics and Growth Frontiers Global Leaders Aviation 100 Technology Innovation of the Year Award 2022.</p>
<p>Aerlytix Analytics Suite was nominated by several aviation industry clients for the Technology Innovation Award, which was awarded based on the product’s innovation and its success in answering the needs of the aviation finance and leasing industry.</p>
<p>Client comments supporting their nominations of the Aerlytix Analytics Suite highlighted the benefits of the maintenance forecast process and the efficiency of the cashflow and maintenance reserve reporting tool, which many noting its flexibility and useability.</p>
<p>The Aerlytix team was praised for their depth of their knowledge of aircraft asset management, lease reporting requirements, and lessor metric priorities, in addition to their technical skills and ability to systemise and automate all these requirements into one intuitive and sophisticated platform.</p>
<p>One of the core pillars of Aerlytix business philosophy is that clients need to spend time making decisions rather than gathering information and data. Employing the Aerlytix centralised data and model eco-system, ensures clients spend time analysing, rather than manually processing, data.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The highlight of the past year has been working with major lessors and investors and supporting them with their operational and business goals. We partner closely with our clients and adapt to their expanding needs as they explore the transformative nature of our technology.</p>
<p><cite>Alan Doyle - Aerlytix CEO</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>The Aerlytix team were also praised for working closely with clients to ensure the smooth integration of the platform, which adapts to the needs of the individual company. “Our strong growth trajectory places high demands on us but rising to meet these challenges is what excites us,” says Alan Doyle, Chief Executive Officer, Aerlytix. “The highlight of the past year has been working with major lessors and investors and supporting them with their operational and business goals. We partner closely with our clients and adapt to their expanding needs as they explore the transformative nature of our technology.”</p>
<p>Aerlytix is delighted to accept the Airline Economics Aviation 100 Technology Innovation Award and looks forward to celebrating with the industry during the Growth Frontiers Dublin Conference from May 9, 2022.</p>

      ]]></content>
    </entry>
	
    
    <entry>
      <title>A fresh new look and website from Aerlytix</title>
      <link href="https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/a-fresh-new-look-and-website-from-aerlytix/"/>
      <updated>2022-01-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/a-fresh-new-look-and-website-from-aerlytix/</id>
      <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Dublin, Ireland – 24th of January, 2022:</strong>: On the same day as Ireland emerged from restrictions due to the Covid-19 pandemic, Aerlytix also emerged with a brand new logo and website.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We are delighted to launch our new website on the same day as the easing of Covid-19 restrictions in Ireland. 2022 promises to be a great year for Aerlytix and our clients.</p>
<p><cite>Alan Doyle - Aerlytix CEO</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>As one of the fastest growing aviation technology companies in Ireland, Aerlytix is spearheading a new direction for the simplification and improvement of aviation finance and leasing processes. The refreshed website sets out the many benefits of the modular Aerlytix Analytics Suite, developed for the aviation finance and leasing industry.</p>
<p>Contact our team today for a more detailed demonstration of the many benefits of the Aerlytix Analytics Suite.</p>

      ]]></content>
    </entry>
	
    
    <entry>
      <title>Head of Quantitative Development at Aerlytix joins CIO Index 2021</title>
      <link href="https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/head-of-quantitative-development-at-aerlytix-joins-cio-index-2021/"/>
      <updated>2021-09-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/head-of-quantitative-development-at-aerlytix-joins-cio-index-2021/</id>
      <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Dublin, Ireland – September 2021:</strong>:  Claudio Viotti, Head of Quantitative Development at Aerlytix, has been included to the Business &amp; Finance CIO 100 Index 2021, produced in association with Equinix.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://businessandfinance.com/cio-100-index-part-1/">Business &amp; Finance CIO 100 Index 2021</a> recognises the top 100 Chief Information Officers working across some of the most innovative companies in Ireland today. As head of quantitative development, Claudio is spearheading Aerlytix efforts that are leading the way in aviation finance technology.</p>
<p>With a degree in aeronautical engineering and a PhD in mathematics from a prestigious US university, plus valuable years of experience in both academic research and commercial technology companies, Claudio was perfectly placed to lead the quantitative effort in this highly capital intensive, complex, yet technology starved industry.</p>
<p>Working closely with his team and clients, Claudio has advanced modelling capabilities using the latest world class technology in ways that the industry has never seen before. His skills, vision and contribution to aviation finance technology are unrivalled in the sector.</p>
<p>“Claudio is a tremendous asset to the firm,” said Alan Doyle, Chief Executive Officer, Aerlytix. “He has worked tirelessly since the company’s inception to create our web-based suite of applications for analyzing and structuring aviation investment and managing aircraft portfolios. We are delighted that Claudio’s efforts have been recognized in the prestigious Business &amp; Finance CIO 100 Index 2021.”</p>

      ]]></content>
    </entry>
	
    
    <entry>
      <title>Aerlytix partners with FlightAware to power new fleet monitoring solution </title>
      <link href="https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/aerlytix-partners-with-flightaware-to-power-new-fleet-monitoring-solution/"/>
      <updated>2021-02-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://www.aerlytix.com/company/news/aerlytix-partners-with-flightaware-to-power-new-fleet-monitoring-solution/</id>
      <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Houston, USA – February 3, 2021:</strong>  Aerlytix, the aviation finance technology specialist, is delighted to announce a partnership with FlightAware, the global provider of flight information and insights, that delivers a new and innovative automated fleet monitoring solution – the Aerlytix Alert Tracker.</p>
<p>The Aerlytix solution was developed by the company in Dublin for the global aviation financing industry using FlightAware's AeroAPI, a query-based engine for accessing real-time, historical and predictive aviation information. By offering access to detailed flight information, the Aerlytix Alert Tracker drives sounder metrics-based decision-making.</p>
<p>As part of its cutting-edge technology platform, which provides industry-leading analytics, the Aerlytix Alert Tracker enables clients to gain an understanding of the performance of any aircraft where the client has an interest.</p>
<p>Alan Doyle, Chief Executive Officer, Aerlytix, said: &quot;Working with FlightAware data gives us the confidence that our clients are getting the best flight data on the market. We are delighted to collaborate with FlightAware on technology solutions that drive simplification by providing quality analytics, processes and controls to clients. Aerlytix is transforming aviation financing with disruptive technology, and this partnership is central to that.&quot;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Aerlytix's use of FlightAware's AeroAPI™ data to power-decisions made by the aviation financing industry is in lock-step with our goal of providing actionable insights through the data we synthesize. By putting the right information in the hands of decision-makers, the tool created through our partnership with Aerlytix offers a unique strategic advantage to users.</p>
<p><cite>Daniel Baker, CEO, FlightAware</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Using an 'exception-based' methodology, the solution enables Aerlytix clients to maintain processes and controls when monitoring fleets, whether they are managed/owned, part of an Asset Backed Security or specific fund. The solution automatically distributes current fleet information to risk, compliance and commercial professionals without the need for creating manual reports.</p>
<p>Aerlytix Alert Tracker automatically alerts clients when their aircraft have not flown for a specified period, when aircraft are flying again or when aircraft have flown into a jurisdiction of interest.</p>
<p>The Aerlytix Alert Tracker simplifies processes through automation whilst delivering productivity wins by freeing resources to work on other value-added activities, and provides near-live outputs and analytics.</p>
<p>Customer Jackson Square Aviation's Chief Technical Officer, Aidan Reynolds, has stated that &quot;this new fleet monitoring solution works really well for us, the implementation was quick and simple.&quot;</p>
<p>Working with FlightAware, Aerlytix looks forward to delivering additional transformative technology to ensure its clients are benefitting from the transparency this software and data provides.</p>

      ]]></content>
    </entry>
	
</feed>